The Gustav Jakob Stoeckel Papers
Yale University Music Library
The Gustav Jakob Stoeckel Papers
1852-1939
MSS 27
Yale University Music Library
3
(7 boxes)
Music, writings, and other materials by and about the German-American composer and teacher Gustav Jakob Stoeckel (1819-1907)
Stoeckel, Gustav Jakob, 1819-1907
Conditions Governing Access
The Papers are open to researchers by appointment. There are no restricted materials in the collection. Please contact the Special Collections staff to schedule an appointment.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Gustav Jakob Stoeckel Papers were bequeathed to the Music Library of Yale University by Stoeckel's daughter, Irene Stoeckel, in 1933.
Arrangement
In 4 series as follows: I. Writings by Stoeckel. II. Miscellaneous items. III. Musical works by Stoeckel. IV. Musical works by others arranged by Stoeckel.
Scope and Contents
The Gustav Jakob Stoeckel Papers contain sketches, manuscript scores, and published editions of Stoeckel's musical compositions, including operas, orchestral works, keyboard pieces, choral music, and songs. The Papers also include Stoeckel's arrangements of music by Battell, Wagner, and Weber. Stoeckel's life and work are further documented by: writings by and about Stoeckel; programs; and miscellaneous items.
Biographical / Historical
Gustav Jakob Stoeckel (or Gustave Jacob Stoeckel, as his name was usually spelled in America) was born in Maikammer in the Bavarian Palatinate on November 9, 1819. He was educated in the Palatinate's two largest cities, Speyer and Kaiserslautern, graduating from the Bischofsschule in the latter. He continued his education with composition lessons from Josef Krebs and was subsequently appointed principal of the gymnasium at Landstuhl. During this period he also served as the cathedral organist in Speyer.
Stoeckel was involved in a political movement based on what David Stanley Smith termed the "subversive, democratic ideas" of men such as Johann Gottfried Kinkel and Carl Schurz, and was forced to flee Germany when his job there was threatened. Landstuhl's loss was Yale's gain, for Stoeckel's arrival in New Haven in 1848 signaled the beginning of a new era for music at the college.
Stoeckel quickly became a prominent musician in New Haven. He began as a private teacher, became Director of the New Haven Musical Association, founded the New Haven Philharmonic Society (a distant ancestor of the New Haven Symphony), and finally opened a private conservatory in 1870. In the words of Luther Noss, "it served, in effect, as Yale's unofficial music department." He staged a Beethoven Festival in the same year, giving the first complete performance in New Haven of the Ninth Symphony.
Stoeckel's association with Yale began in 1855, when he was appointed Instructor in Vocal Music through the efforts of Irene Battell Larned. His responsibilities grew in 1856 when he was made Organist and Chapel Master. In 1864 he was awarded the first honorary Doctor of Music degree at Yale. From 1868 to 1874 he directed both the Chapel Choir and the Glee Club; Thomas G. Shepard took over the Glee Club in 1874. Stoeckel organized the orchestra, played the organ at Sunday services and in recitals, and taught many undergraduates privately. In spite of all this it was not until 1890 that he was officially listed as a member of the faculty, although his courses in sight-singing had occasionally appeared in the course catalogue. In 1890, a "Musical Department" was formally established, and Stoeckel was finally appointed Professor of Music. He retired in 1894.
Besides his activities as a teacher, performer, and administrator, Stoeckel was also a composer. He completed six operas: Harold, Lichtenstein, Mahomet, Miles Standish, Miskodita, and Münchhausen. All except Miles Standish are in German. Stoeckel's operas were greatly influenced by Wagner's. (Stoeckel attended the opening of the Bayreuth Festspielhaus in 1876, and wrote an article after his visit.) Like Wagner, Stoeckel served as his own librettist, and all of his operas except the earliest feature continuous music throughout each act.
Gustav Jakob Stoeckel died in Norfolk, Connecticut on May 17, 1907.
Music -- United States -- 19th century; Operas -- Scores; Piano music; Songs; Stoeckel, Gustav Jakob, 1819-1907
- Writings by Stoeckel, Series I
  General
  Includes nonmusical works by or about Stoeckel.
  It is divided into two subseries:
  A. Prose
  B. Poems
  - Prose, I.A
    - Battell Professorship of Music. Inaugural Address by Dr. Gustave J. Stoeckel, with Program of Exercises at the Opening of the Music Rooms. -- New Haven: Tuttle, Morehouse & Taylor, Printers, 1890., 1 item; 18 p.; 28 cm. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Typescript.
    - "Wagner Festival at Bayreuth" / by Gustave J. Stoeckel, Mus. D., Yale College., 1 item; pp. 258-293. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Photocopy of article appearing in The New Englander, Vol. 36, 1877. New Haven: W.L. Kingsley. Original in Sterling Library.
    - Address on the occasion... (Box 1, Folder 1)
      See: II. MISCELLANEOUS ITEMS. Smith, David Stanley.
    - Notebook, 1 item; [83], [70] p.; 21 cm. (Box 10, Folder 78)
      Contains 2 lectures: "Church music"; and "American National Opera."
      Page [29] of "American National Opera" is signed and dated "Dec 6th 1889."
      Gift of Robert A. Lehman, 1982 Jul.
      Added to the papers 1982 Jul.
  - Poems, I.B
    - Abraham Lincoln., 1 item; [3] leaves.; 32 cm. (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Holograph signed.
      At end: Norfolk, Conn.
    - General Grant., 1 item; [2] leaves.; 32 cm. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Holograph.
- Miscellaneous items, Series II
  - In Memoriam Prof. Gustave J. Stoeckel, May 17 1907.; 1 item; [23] p.; 32 cm. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Contents: Collection of clippings of obituary notices, mounted on a blank book. Title supplied by Burrelle's Press clipping Bureau?: typed letter signed from Marshall Bartholomew to Eva O'Meara, 1952 May 3, laid in (1 leaf.)
  - Programme of the Grand Combination Concert for the aid of wounded in the Franco-German War, at Music Hall, Monday, September 19th, 1870. Conducted by Stoeckel., 1 item; [4] p.; 22 cm. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    English & German words.
  - Gustave J. Stoeckel: Yale Pioneer in Music / by David Stanley Smith. Battell Professor of Music in Yale University -- New Haven: Published for the School of Music, Yale University: Yale University Press, 1939., Smith, David Stanley, 1877-1949; 1 item; 31 p.: port.; 24 cm. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Includes appendices: List of original compositions by Dr. Stoeckel in the Library of the Yale School of Music (3 p.); Excerpts from Dr. Stoeckel's Address on the Occasion of the Opening of the Music Rooms in the Yale Treasury Building, April 28, 1890 (4 p.)
  - Program for the Grand Beethoven Festival at Music Hall, New Haven, Conn. 1870 Dec 5-7. (Box 8)
    (added 10/26/81)
  - Biographical material (Box 8)
    Loose sheets (15p.)
    Manuscript and typescript.
  - Autograph letter signed to his father, Gustave J. Stoeckel, 1890 May 6.; Stoeckel, Carl, 1858-1925; 1 item (Box 8)
    (added 1982 Jul)
  - Receipt from Yale College for payment to Gustave J. Stoeckel for providing commencement music., 1 item; 1 sheet; 21 cm. (Box 8)
    Manuscript in ink.
  - Miscellaneous items (Box 8)
- Musical works by Stoeckel, Series III
  Contains holographs, manuscripts, facsimiles, and published works. Arranged alphabetically by title.
  - A day of sunshine. Cantata for male voices., 1 item; chorus score ([10] p.); 34 cm. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Librettist unidentified.
  - Absence. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    See: Songs. Absence.
  - [Ah welaway] Ah welaway., 2 items; chorus score ([2] leaves); 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    For chorus (TTBB)
    Librettist unidentified. Contains quote from Goethe.
  - Ah welaway., chorus score ([2] leaves); 34 cm. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Alice. Redowa. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    See: Ländler.
  - [Anthem. Psalm 67] Anthem. Psalm 67., 2 items; vocal score (V leaves.); 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    On cover: "... New Haven, Conn.," with unidentified poem.
  - Anthem. Psalm 67., vocal score (123 leaves); 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Incomplete.
  - ... Anthem and Te Deum = Dedication Anthem by Gustave J. Stoeckel. -- [New Haven?]: Punderson & Crisand, Printers, [1876?], vocal score (9 p.); 36 cm. (Box 1, Folder 10-11 2)
    Latin words.
    Title on cover: Yale College. Dedication of the Battell Chapel. Anthem and Te Deum by Gustave J. Stoeckel.
    Facsimile.
    Two copies, one inscribed to Mrs. Irene Larned, the other to Robbins Battell, by Stoeckel.
  - Anthems for male voices / arranged by Gustave J. Stoeckel. -- [New Haven?]: L.S. Punderson, Lithographer and Printer, 1881., 2 items; chorus score (48 p.); 24 cm. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Includes an untitled piece for organ, holograph? ([5] p.), and sketch ([2] p.)
    Two copies.
  - Aus der Ferne. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    See: Songs. Aus der Ferne.
  - Benedictus. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    See: Works. Selections.
  - Beware. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    See: Songs. Beware.
  - Bonum est. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - The Chimes of Norfolk. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    See: Songs. The Chimes of Norfolk.
  - [Choral music. Selections; arr.], 1 item; 1 v. (various pagings), bound; 30 cm. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    English words.
  - Church melodies for the College Hymnal / arranged by Gustave J. Stoeckel. -- New Haven, Conn.: Punderson & Crisand, Printers and Lithographers, 1876., 1 item; viii, 103 p. [interleaved, with pages ruled for the music]; facsimile. [music only] (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Annotations added to index.
    Another copy: Rare M 2117 S871
  - Crambambuli. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    See: Songs of Germany.
  - Deus miseratur. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - The Fairies, fantasie romantique / Gustave J. Stoeckel. -- New York: Paul K. Weizel, 1852., 1 item; 9 p.; 33 cm. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Title on cover: To Mr. W.A. Larned...
  - Farewell & infidelity. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - ... Fishermaiden. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    See: Songs. ... Fishermaiden.
  - Gloria in excelsis Deo. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Die grösste Künstler im Künstlerthem / Gustave J. Stoeckel., 1 item; score (10, 83 p.), bound; 36 cm. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - [Harold] Harold. Der letzte Sachsenkönig. Pro Patria = Harold., 4 items; score (424 p.), bound; 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Libretto by Stoeckel; German and English words.
  - [Harold] Harold. Der letzte Sachsenkönig = Harold. Der letzte Sachsenkönig. Pro Patria., vocal score (118 p.), bound; 34 cm. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    German and English words.
  - [Harold] Harold. Der letzte Sachsenkönig., 65 [ie. 66] p., bound; 26 cm. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Libretto; German words.
  - [Harold] Harold. The last of the Saxon Kings = Harold., 54 p., bound; 27 cm. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Libretto; English words.
    Untitled poem laid in ([1] leaf.)
  - I'se a travelin' to de grave. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    See: Songs. I'se a travelin' to de grave.
  - Jubilate Deo. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Keep me from sinkin' down. Solo and chorus / with accompaniment by Gustave J. Stoeckel. -- Boston: Published by Robbins Battell by Oliver Ditson & Co., 1868., 1 item; 5 p.; 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 20)
    For solo voice and chorus (SATB)
  - Ländler = Alice Redowa / Gustave J. Stoeckel. -- Brooklyn: P.K. Weizel, 1853., 1 item; 6 [ie. 7] p.; 34 cm. (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Title on cover: To Miss Alice Edwards of New Haven, Conn. Alice Redowa for the piano, by Gustave J. Stoeckel...
  - [Lichtenstein] Lichtenstein. Oper in drei Auszügen., 1 item; [2] leaves., score ([408] p.), bound; 34 cm. (Box 2, Folder 21)
    German words.
    At end: Fine den 4 Sept 1861, Stoeckel.
  - [Lichtenstein] Lichtenstein. Klavier Auszug. [binder'stitle], 1 item; vocal score ([167] p.), bound; 34 cm. (Box 3)
  - Lily bells. (Box 3)
    See: Songs. Lily bells.
  - [Mahomet] Mahomet. Oper in 5 Auszügen., 4 items; [16] p., score (III, 517 p.), bound; 34 cm. (Box 3)
    Libretto by Stoeckel at beginning ([16] p.); German words.
  - [Mahomet] Mahomet. Oper in 5 Auszügen / von Gustave J. Stoeckel., [1] leaf., vocal score (164 p.), [1] leaf, bound; 34 cm. (Box 3)
  - [Mahomet. Overture] Ouverture., 2 items; score ([75] p.); 34 cm. (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Contains revisions in pencil.
  - Mahomet, Ouverture., score (47 p.), bound; 35 cm. (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Different version.
  - Martha, Mazurka de Salon. dediée à Mlle. Martha Read / par Gustave J. Stoeckel. -- Brooklyn: Paul K. Weizel, 1855., 1 item; 7 p.; 33 cm. (Box 3, Folder 23)
    For piano.
    Contains fingerings in pencil.
    Op. 12.
  - [Maud] Maud / Gustave J. Stoeckel., 2 items; V p.; 34 cm. (Box 3, Folder 24)
    At end: july 14, 1880.
  - [Maud] Maud. Episode for the Piano / Gustave J. Stoeckel., [4] leaves.; 35 cm. (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - [Miles Standish] Miles Standish., 5 items; score (400 p., 1 leaf.), bound; 35 cm. (Box 4)
    Libretto by Stoeckel: German words. Not Longfellow's poem.
    At end: Ende des 1ten Abend.
  - [Miles Standish] Miles Standish / Gustave J. Stoeckel., score (3 v.), bound; 35 cm. (Box 4, Folder 25-26)
    At end: Ende des 1sten Abend.
  - [Miles Standish] Miles Standish / by (Gustave) Jacob Stoeckel., vocal score ([2] leaves., 179 p.), bound; 34 cm. (Box 4, Folder 27)
    At end: The end of the first evening.
  - [Miles Standish] Miles Standish., vocal score (vi, 77 p.), bound; 35 cm. (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - [Miles Standish] Miles Standish. Opera in three acts., 54 [ie. 50] p., bound; 27 cm. (Box 4, Folder 28)
    Libretto; German and English words in parallel titles.
  - [Miskodita] Miskodita / Gustave J. Stoeckel., 6 items; 23 p., score (258 p.), bound; 34 cm. (Box 5, Folder 29)
    Libretto by Stoeckel; German words. Sequel to his Miles Standish.
    At end: Den 4 der November 1896
  - [Miskodita] Miskodita., condensed score (112 p.), bound; 35 cm. (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - [Miskodita] Miskodita (2ten Abend), vocal score (78 p.), bound; 35 cm. (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - [Miskodita] Miskodita., vocal score (67 p.), bound; 35 cm. (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - [Miskodita] Miskodita. I. Sketch., vocal score (65 p.), bound; 35 cm. (Box 5, Folder 33)
    On title page and at end: directions to the binder.
  - [Miskodita] Introduction to second scene "Miskodita" / Gustave J. Stoeckel., score (12 p.) + 16 parts [string parts are photocopies]; 32 cm. (Box 5, Folder 34-35)
    Manuscript in copyist's hand? ["Hugo Kortschak" is stamped in right hand corner]
    Cover of envelope in which the above was enclosed is laid in. Contains note from Hugo Kortschak.
  - Mountaineer's farewell. (Box 5, Folder 34-35)
    See: Songs. Mountaineer's farewell.
  - [Münchhausen] Münchhausen., 4 items; score (414 p.), bound; 35 cm. (Box 5, Folder 34-35)
    Libretto by Stoeckel; German words.
  - [Münchhausen] Münchhausen. Klavierauszug., iii, vocal score (144 p.), bound; 35 cm. (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - [Münchhausen] Münchhausen., vocal score (190 p.), bound; 35 cm. (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - [Münchhausen] Münchhausen., 26 p., bound; 35 cm. (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - [Robin Adair] Robin Adair. Concert Fantasia for organ / Gustave J. Stoeckel., 1 item; [1] leaf.; 35 cm. (Box 6, Folder 38)
    Holograph of sketch.
  - Sabbath evening. (Box 6, Folder 38)
    See: Songs. Sabbath evening.
  - Sacred music... (Box 6, Folder 38)
    Catalogued separately: Rare M 2117 S871 S12
  - [St. Agnes' Eve] St. Agnes' Eve., 3 items; chorus score (vii p. [ie. 6]); 35 cm. (Box 6, Folder 39)
    For baritone and chorus (TTBB) unacc.
  - [St. Agnes' Eve] St. Agnes' Eve., chorus score (vii p.); 34 cm. (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - [St. Agnes' Eve] St. Agnes' Eve., chorus score ([4] p.); 34 cm. (Box 6, Folder 39)
    For baritone and chorus unacc.
  - [Songs] Absence, by Longfellow / composed by Gustave J. Stoeckel, op. 11. -- Brooklyn: Paul K. Weizel, 1855., 1 item (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - [Songs] Aus der Ferne / G.J. Stoeckel. -- [S.l]: [s.n.], 1 item; 10 p.; 33 cm. (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - [Songs] Beware = Diebstahl / Gustave J. Stoeckel, op. 9, no. 4. -- Brooklyn: P.K. Weizel, 1853., 1 item; 7 p.; 34 cm. (Box 6, Folder 42)
    English and German words.
    On cover: "Irene Larned."
  - [Songs] The Chimes of Norfolk. An Idyl / G.J. Stoeckel. -- New York: W.A. Pond & Co., 1893., 1 item; 7 p.; 36 cm. (Box 6, Folder 43)
    Title on cover: To my friend Robbins Battell Esq... Words and music by Gustave J. Stoeckel.
  - [Songs] ...Fishermaiden, by Heine / composed by Gustave J. Stoeckel. Op. 11. No. 2. -- Brooklyn: P.K. Weizel, 1855., 1 item; 5 p.; 33 cm. (Box 6, Folder 44)
    On p. 1: To his friend, William G. Webster.
  - [Songs] I'se a travelin' to de grave. Southern Melody / accompaniment by Gustave J. Stoeckel. -- Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co., 1867., 2 items; 5 p.; 36 cm. (Box 6, Folder 45)
    Note on front cover.
    Two copies, one is cut down to 32 cm.
  - [Songs] Lily Bells = Mayenglöckchen / Gustave J. Stoeckel. Op. 9. no. 3. -- Brooklyn: Paul K. Weizel, 1853., 1 item; 5 p.; 34 cm. (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - [Songs] Mountaineer's Farewell - Mein Herz ist im Hochland / Gustave J. Stoeckel. Op. 9. No. 1. -- Brooklyn: Paul K. Weizel, 1853., 1 item (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - [Songs] Sabbath evening / composed by Gustave J. Stoeckel. ouvre 10. Written by Leonard W. Bacon. -- Brooklyn: P.K. Weizel, 1855., 1 item; 5 p.; 33 cm. (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - [Songs] Sunday morning - Sonntags Fruehe / Gustave J. Stoeckel. Op. 9. No. 2 -- Brooklyn: Paul K. Weizel, 1853., 1 item; 5 p.; 4 cm. (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - [Songs] The Violet's grave = Des Veilchen's Grab. Manuscript / Gustave J. Stoeckel, op. 7, No. 1., 1 item; [3] p.; 35 cm. (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - [Songs] The Violet's Grave = Des Veilchen's Grab / Gustave J. Stoeckel, op. 7, No. 1. -- Brooklyn: P.K. Weizel, Esq. The Violet's Grave Nocturne., 1 item (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - [Songs] What sounds so sweet wake me? = Ständchen / Music composed by Gustave J. Stoeckel, op. 7, No. 2 / Poem by Upland / English version by Longfellow., 1 item; 5 p.; 34 cm. (Box 6, Folder 51)
    Title on cover: To his friend Paul K. Weizel
  - [Songs] Woodman, spare that tree / poetry by G.P. Morris, Music by Gustave J. Stoeckel. M.D., 1 item; [1] leaf.; 35 cm. (Box 6, Folder 52)
    Note: Old favorite in modern dress. No. 1.
  - [Songs of Germany] Farewell & Infidelity / Gustave J. Stoeckel, op. 5, No. 1. -- Brooklyn: P.K. Weizel, 1852., 1 item; 9 p.; 34 cm. (Box 6, Folder 53)
    Title on cover: ... Paraphrases for the piano composed and dedicated to the ladies of Miss M. Dutton's Female Seminary, New Haven...
  - [Songs] Crambambuli / Gustave J. Stoeckel, op. 5, No. 2. -- Brooklyn: P.K. Weizel, 1852., 1 item; [3] p.; 34 cm. (Box 6, Folder 53)
    Title on cover: same as above.
  - Studenten-Leben. Ouverture / G.J. Stoeckel., 1 item; 21 parts [only] (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Sunday morning. (Box 6, Folder 54)
    See: Songs. Sunday morning.
  - [Tam O' Shanter] Tam O' Shanter / F.K. Stoeckel., 2 items; score ([122] p.), bound; 35 cm. (Box 7)
    For orchestra.
  - [Tam O' Shanter] Tam O' Shanter. Symphonie für Grössten Orchester / Gustave J. Stoeckel., score (122 p.), bound; 39 cm. (Box 7)
    At end: den 8ten October 1874
  - Der Temperament., 1 item; vii p.; 34 cm. (Box 7, Folder 55)
    At end: August 22nd 1879...?
  - Torringford Te Deum / Gustave J. Stoeckel., 1 item; chorus score (vii p.); 35 cm. (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - The violet's grave. (Box 7, Folder 56)
    See: Songs. The violet's grave.
  - What sounds so sweet wake me? (Box 7, Folder 56)
    See: Songs. What sounds so sweet wake me?
  - Miscellaneous instrumental works, etc., 1 item; [65] p.; 28 x 34 cm. (Box 7, Folder 57)
    Cover title: Compositionen für...
    Contains pieces by Stoeckel for wind band, for piano, and for voice; also works by others arranged by Stoeckel, and unidentified sketches.
  - Miscellaneous sacred works, etc. (Box 7, Folder 58)
    Holographs, in part signed.
    Contents: Deus miseratur; Jubilate Deo; Gloria in Excelsis Deo; Bonum est; Benedictus; and an unidentified piece.
  - Woodman, spare that tree. (Box 7, Folder 58)
    See: Songs. Woodman, spare that tree.
  - [Tam O'Shanter], 46 parts; 35 cm. (Box 8)
    Manuscript
    Item found and added 1981 Jul-1982 Apr
  - [Miles Standish] (Box 9; 10, Folder 61-67; 68-70)
    score (xxxix p.); 34 cm.
    Holograph signed, in ink.
    39 parts; 35 cm.
    61 parts; 35 cm.
    Includes 7 voice parts.
    Items found and added 1981 Jul-1982 Apr
  - [Tam O'Shanter] Libretto. German., 11 p.; 35 cm. (Box 9; 10, Folder 61-67; 68-70)
    Holograph in ink.
  - [Mahomet] Chorus aus Mahomet, 1 flute part; 35 cm. (Box 10, Folder 71)
  - [Mahomet] Marsch aus Mahomet, score (3, [12] p.); 35 cm. (Box 10, Folder 72)
    Incomplete, lacking last pages.
    16 parts; 35 cm.
  - [Mahomet] Introduction to Aria from Mahomet, score ([4] p.); 35 cm. (Box 10, Folder 73)
    8 parts; 18-35 cm.
  - [Mahomet} Overture, condensed score ([25] p.); 35 cm. (Box 10, Folder 74)
  - [Mahomet] Overture, 57 parts; 35 cm. (Box 10, Folder 75-76)
    Holographs signed, and manuscript in ink.
  - [Mahomet] Quartet and chorus from "Mahomet" S.l.: s.n., n.d., 1 close score (5 p.); 36 cm. (Box 10, Folder 77)
    For solo voices and chorus (SATB).
    Four copies.
  - [Miles Standish. Selections] Introduction to 2nd scene of "Miles Standish", 8 items; 8 string parts; 34 cm. (Box 4, Folder 28)
    Manuscript in ink with additions in blue pencil.
    Includes: Vln I (3); V II (2); Vla; and Vlc (2).
    Items added as of 1982 Jul
  - [Miskodita. Selections] Introduction to 2nd scene, "Miskodita", 31 items; 31 string parts; 33 cm. (Box 5, Folder 35)
    Manuscript in ink and copies.
    Includes 5 manuscript parts - originals and 26 copies.
- Musical works by others arranged by Stoeckel, Series IV
  - Chorus from Tannhäuser / arranged by Prof. G.J. Stoeckel, for the Mendelssohn Society, N.H. -- [S.l.]: [s.n.], n.d., Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883; 1 item; 1 chorus score ([4] p.); 36 cm. (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Ouverture: Der Freischütz / Carl M. v. Weber., Weber, Carl Maria von, 1786-1826; 1 item; 1 score (52 p.); 34 cm. (Box 7, Folder 60)
    Manuscript in Stoeckel's hand.
  - Freedmen's Quickstep: composed for the Norfolk (Conn.) Band / by Robbins Battell; arranged for the piano by Gustave J. Stoeckel. -- New York: Wm. A. Pond, 1863., Battell, Robbins, 1819-1895; 5 p. of music; 36 cm. (Box 8)
    Five copies.
    Added to the papers 1981 Jul 14.